Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson here with us at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be in one of my favorite sporting events, which is?
今天我们要聊我最喜欢的体育赛事之一，是什么呢？
F1, of course.
当然是F1。
F1 racing, alright.
F1赛车，没错。
So yeah, we're going to be talking about racing, specifically F1, which is a very popular sport
所以，我们要讨论赛车，特别是F1，这是一项非常受欢迎的运动，
all over the world.
全世界都很流行。
Yeah, I think maybe it's like number two in popularity after soccer.
是啊，我觉得它可能仅次于足球，排第二。
Yeah, I think so.
嗯，我也这么觉得。
I have no numbers to back that up though.
不过我可没有数据支持这个说法。
Well they do travel everywhere, they have races all over the world and just people love
他们确实到处跑，在世界各地都有比赛，而且人们就是喜欢
it.
它。
Well, it is kind of a cool thing.
嗯，这确实挺酷的。
Well, going 300 kilometers per hour in a car is pretty cool.
是啊，开着车以每小时300公里的速度行驶，确实很酷。
Alright, so let's not delay this any longer.
好了，我们别再耽搁了。
Let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
让我们第一次听一下对话。
Welcome back racing fans, my name is Rick Fields and as always I'm joined by my partner
欢迎回来，赛车迷们，我是Rick Fields，和往常一样，我的搭档
in crime, Bob Copeland.
Bob Copeland也在这里。
We're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimi Raikonen is leading the pack
我们正处于这场激动人心的比赛的最后阶段，Kimi Raikonen领先
with only four laps to go.
整个车队，只剩下四圈了。
They're heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Raikonen.
他们正驶向三号弯，Lewis Hamilton试图超越Raikonen。
It's a close one and oh no, Hamilton hits the wall.
非常接近，哦不，Hamilton撞墙了。
He came in too fast, jammed on the brakes and spun out.
他进弯太快，猛踩刹车，然后打滑失控了。
We have a yellow flag and the pace car is making its way onto the track.
黄旗挥动，安全车正在驶上赛道。
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops.
清理人员正在拖走严重受损的赛车，绿旗落下。
Raikonen is still in the lead with only two laps to go.
Raikonen仍然领先，只剩下两圈了。
Smoke is coming out of his car.
他的车冒烟了。
He seems to be having engine trouble.
他好像引擎出了问题。
He makes his way under the pit and Fernando Alonso takes the lead.
他驶入维修区，Fernando Alonso取得了领先。
How unlucky for Raikonen and this race is over, ladies and gentlemen.
Raikonen真是太不走运了，女士们先生们，比赛结束了。
Alonso takes the checkered flag.
Alonso冲过终点线，拿下方格旗。
What an exciting race.
多么激动人心的比赛啊。
I always love a good crash when it comes to car races.
说到赛车比赛，我总是喜欢看精彩的撞车。
I think many people go to races expecting to see a crash.
我觉得很多人去看比赛就是期待看到撞车。
They don't want to see people getting hurt.
他们不想看到有人受伤。
No, but a little bit of...
不，但一点点……
The emotion of just car crashes and stuff.
那种撞车带来的刺激感之类的。
Yeah, a little explosion here and there.
是啊，偶尔来点小爆炸什么的。
Alright.
好吧。
So, now we saw some really exciting language related to racing.
那么，现在我们看到了一些与赛车相关的非常生动的语言。
So why don't we look at that now in Language Takeaway.
所以我们不如在“语言要点”环节来看看这些内容。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, so we were talking about that crash and I think what led to the crash was the
好的，我们刚才谈到了那次撞车，我认为导致撞车的原因是
driver jammed on the brakes.
车手猛踩了刹车。
Right.
对。
He jammed on the brakes.
他猛踩了刹车。
To jam on the brakes.
猛踩刹车。
Okay.
好的。
Now, if I jam on the brakes...
那么，如果我猛踩刹车……
You push the brakes really, really hard and really quickly and really suddenly.
就是非常用力、非常快、非常突然地踩刹车。
Right.
对。
So you jam on the brakes and you stop very quickly.
所以你猛踩刹车，然后很快停下来。
So Lewis Hamilton jammed on the brakes and consequently spun out.
所以Lewis Hamilton猛踩刹车，结果打滑失控了。
To spin out.
打滑失控。
Okay.
好的。
In the present, it would be spin out.
现在时态是spin out。
Spin out.
Spin out。
Okay.
好的。
So, imagine yourselves driving your car on a very wet road.
那么，想象一下你在非常湿滑的路上开车。
And then you jam on the brakes.
然后你猛踩刹车。
Right.
对。
So then the car, you kind of lose control of the car and it starts to spin.
然后车就会有点失控，开始打转。
It goes in circles.
它会转圈。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
That would be to spin out.
那就是打滑失控。
This has actually happened to me more than once.
这其实在我身上发生过不止一次。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Were you okay?
你没事吧？
Yeah, I was fine.
嗯，我没事。
I was fine.
我没事。
Okay.
好的。
So, the car spun out.
所以，车打滑失控了。
Now, in racing, you always see this really cool car come out and be ahead of everyone
在赛车中，你总是会看到一辆很酷的车在发生事故时
when there's an accident.
出来，领先所有人。
Right.
对。
That's called the pace car.
那叫安全车。
The pace car.
安全车。
Pace car.
Now, why is it called the pace car?
那么，为什么叫安全车呢？
Because it sets the pace.
因为它设定速度。
Okay.
好的。
The pace or the speed.
速度或速率。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
So, pace means speed.
所以pace就是速度的意思。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
So, the car spun out and no other car can pass it.
所以车打滑失控后，其他车都不能超过它。
Everyone must go at the same speed.
所有人都必须以同样的速度行驶。
Right.
对。
The pace car.
安全车。
Pace car.
All right.
好的。
So, after there's an accident, the cleanup crew must come out.
那么，事故发生后，清理人员必须出来。
Okay.
好的。
Cleanup crew.
清理人员。
All right.
好的。
So, crew, this is an interesting word.
所以，crew这个词很有意思。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
When we talk about a crew, we talk about a group of people who work together.
当我们说crew时，我们指的是一群一起工作的人。
Okay.
好的。
But, for example, in an office, can I have a crew?
但是，比如说在办公室里，我能说crew吗？
Not really.
不太行。
Not commonly, right?
不常见，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
People work together and they use their hands to work.
人们一起工作，用手干活。
They do manual labor.
他们做体力劳动。
Okay.
好的。
So, I can say, for example, a construction crew.
所以，我可以举个例子，比如建筑工人。
That's right.
没错。
Or maybe the ground crew at the airport.
或者机场的地勤人员。
Okay.
好的。
Or the flight crew.
或者机组人员。
Also at the airport.
也是在机场。
All right.
好的。
Well, in the airplane.
嗯，在飞机上。
So, that's a crew.
那就是crew。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
So, cleanup crew.
所以，清理人员。
Cleanup crew.
清理人员。
Now, they came out to take that car away, that broken or damaged vehicle.
现在，他们出来把那辆坏掉或受损的车拖走。
So, they were towing it.
所以他们是在拖车。
Tow.
拖。
Okay.
好的。
The verb to tow.
动词to tow。
To tow.
To tow。
So, what does it mean when you tow something or you tow a car?
那么，当你拖东西或拖车时，是什么意思？
You pull something behind you.
你把某物拉在你后面。
So, if you're a truck, that might pull a car behind you.
所以，如果你是一辆卡车，你可能会把一辆车拉在后面。
That's a tow truck.
那就是拖车。
A tow truck.
拖车。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Now, this happens commonly if you park your vehicle where you are not supposed to.
这种情况通常发生在你把车停在不能停的地方时。
That's right.
没错。
And your car will get towed.
然后你的车会被拖走。
Your car gets towed.
你的车被拖走了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好的。
So, we saw five really great words related to racing.
那么，我们看到了五个与赛车相关的非常好的词。
And now, why don't we listen to our dialogue again and then we'll look at some other interesting
现在，我们为什么不再次听一下对话，然后看看其他一些有趣的
phrases.
短语。
Welcome back, race fans.
欢迎回来，赛车迷们。
My name is Rick Fields.
我是Rick Fields。
And as always, I'm joined by my partner in crime, Bob Copeland.
和往常一样，我的搭档Bob Copeland也在这里。
We're in the last stretch of this very exciting race.
我们正处于这场激动人心的比赛的最后阶段。
And Kimi Raikonen is leading the pack with only four laps to go.
Kimi Raikonen领先整个车队，只剩下四圈了。
They are heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Raikonen.
他们正驶向三号弯，Lewis Hamilton试图超越Raikonen。
It's a close one and oh no, Hamilton hits the wall.
非常接近，哦不，Hamilton撞墙了。
He came in too fast, jammed on the brakes and spun out.
他进弯太快，猛踩刹车，然后打滑失控了。
We have a yellow flag and the pace car is making its way onto the track.
黄旗挥动，安全车正在驶上赛道。
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops.
清理人员正在拖走严重受损的赛车，绿旗落下。
Raikonen is still in the lead with only two laps to go.
Raikonen仍然领先，只剩下两圈了。
Smoke is coming out of his car.
他的车冒烟了。
He seems to be having engine trouble.
他好像引擎出了问题。
He makes his way into the pit and Fernando Alonso takes the lead.
他驶入维修区，Fernando Alonso取得了领先。
How unlucky for Raikonen.
Raikonen真是太不走运了。
And this race is over, ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们，比赛结束了。
Alonso takes the checkered flag.
Alonso冲过终点线，拿下方格旗。
Okay.
好的。
So now we're back and I think it's time for us to take a look at some phrases in FluencyBuilder.
现在我们回来了，我觉得是时候看看“流利度构建”环节的一些短语了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Well, even though we're talking about F1 racing, a lot of the language can be used
嗯，虽然我们在谈论F1赛车，但很多语言
in many different situations.
可以用在很多不同的场合。
So let's look at some of those phrases now.
所以我们现在来看看其中一些短语。
When Rick Fields introduced his co-host, he said, my partner in crime.
当Rick Fields介绍他的搭档时，他说，我的partner in crime。
Partner in crime.
Partner in crime。
Now, it's not that they're actually committing a crime.
这可不是说他们真的在犯罪。
No, they're not actually bank robbers.
不，他们不是真的银行劫匪。
But it's a very common and friendly way of saying my good friend or my...
但这是一种非常常见且友好的方式，表示我的好朋友或我的……
The person I do everything with.
和我一起做所有事情的人。
Right, my co-worker, for example.
对，比如我的同事。
But a co-worker who's a really, really good friend, who you spend a lot of time with.
但是一个关系非常好、经常在一起的同事。
Okay.
好的。
So that's your partner in crime.
那就是你的partner in crime。
It's just a metaphor, right?
这只是一个比喻，对吧？
So partner in crime.
所以是partner in crime。
Now what about the next phrase?
那下一个短语呢？
The last stretch.
The last stretch。
Last stretch.
Last stretch。
Okay, before we explain this word, let's listen to some examples and then we'll come back
好的，在我们解释这个词之前，先听一些例子，然后我们再回来
and talk about it.
讨论。
Example one.
例子一。
We are finally in the last stretch of a very long week.
我们终于到了漫长一周的最后阶段。
I can't wait to go home.
我等不及要回家了。
Example two.
例子二。
He's in the last stretch of his college years and soon he'll graduate.
他正处于大学时光的最后阶段，很快就要毕业了。
Okay, so I understand that to mean like the final length of time.
好的，我理解那意思是最后一段时间。
Right.
对。
The last or final moments before an ending.
结束前的最后或最终时刻。
All right, so the last stretch.
好的，所以是the last stretch。
The last stretch.
The last stretch。
Now when you're on the last stretch, you just have a few minutes to go.
当你处于最后阶段时，你只剩下几分钟了。
To go.
剩下。
Yeah, to go.
是啊，剩下。
Now this preposition to and the verb go is very easy, right?
这个介词to和动词go很简单，对吧？
Right.
对。
But if you say five minutes to go, what does that mean?
但如果你说“还有五分钟”，那是什么意思？
Five minutes left.
还剩五分钟。
Left.
剩下。
It doesn't mean it's five minutes to actually leave, right?
它不是说还有五分钟就要离开，对吧？
Right.
对。
It means you must complete five minutes before you can be finished.
它的意思是你必须完成五分钟才能结束。
Okay.
好的。
So it's not about exiting.
所以不是关于离开。
Right.
对。
I have five days to go before I go on vacation.
我还有五天就要去度假了。
So it's not about you actually going on the vacation, it's about you passing those five
所以不是你真的要去度假，而是你度过那五天
days.
时间。
Can you give us another example?
你能再给我们举个例子吗？
How about we have 45 minutes to go before the end of the day.
比如我们还有45分钟就到一天结束了。
That's right.
没错。
So to go.
所以“to go”。
Left.
剩下。
Exactly.
正是。
To go.
“To go”。
Now let's take a look at our last phrase.
现在让我们看看最后一个短语。
Close one.
好险。
A close one.
All right.
好了。
Another interesting phrase made up of simple words.
另一个由简单词组成的有趣短语。
So let's listen to some examples to help us understand it.
所以让我们听一些例子来帮助理解它。
Example one.
例子一。
That was a close one.
好险啊。
The teacher almost caught me cheating.
老师差点抓到我作弊。
Example two.
例子二。
It's a close one.
真险。
The sun is up and the tide and the game is almost over.
太阳出来了，潮水涨了，比赛也快结束了。
Example three.
例子三。
My girlfriend almost found the presents I hid under the bed.
我女朋友差点发现我藏在床下的礼物。
It was a close one.
好险。
Okay.
好的。
So a close one, it means?
所以“a close one”意思是？
A situation that is almost dangerous but wasn't.
一种几乎危险但实际没有发生的状况。
But wasn't.
但没有发生。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
正是。
That was a close one.
好险啊。
Okay.
好的。
So very good phrases.
所以这些短语非常好。
I think we can take a lot from this and apply it outside of F1, right?
我觉得我们可以从中收获很多，并应用到F1之外，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好了。
So let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk about
那么让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来聊聊
this great sport.
这项伟大的运动。
Welcome back racing fans.
欢迎回来，赛车迷们。
My name is Rick Fields and as always I'm joined by my partner in crime, Bob Copeland.
我是Rick Fields，和我一起的还有我的搭档Bob Copeland。
We're in the last stretch of this very exciting race and Kimi Raikkonen is leading the pack
我们正处于这场激动人心的比赛的最后阶段，Kimi Raikkonen领先，
with only four laps to go.
只剩下四圈了。
They're heading to turn three and Lewis Hamilton tries to pass Raikkonen.
他们正驶向三号弯，Lewis Hamilton试图超越Raikkonen。
It's a close one and oh no, Hamilton hits the wall.
好险，哦不，Hamilton撞墙了。
He came in too fast, jammed on the brakes and spun out.
他进弯太快，猛踩刹车，然后打滑了。
We have yellow flag and the pace car is making its way into the track.
黄旗挥动，安全车正在驶入赛道。
The cleanup crew is towing the heavily damaged car and the green flag drops.
清理人员正在拖走严重受损的赛车，绿旗落下。
Raikkonen is still in the lead with only two laps to go.
Raikkonen仍然领先，只剩下两圈了。
Smoke is coming out of his car.
他的车冒烟了。
He seems to be having engine trouble.
他好像引擎出了问题。
He makes his way under the pit and Fernando Alonso takes the lead.
他驶入维修区，Fernando Alonso取得领先。
Now unlucky for Raikkonen and this race is over ladies and gentlemen.
现在Raikkonen运气不佳，女士们先生们，比赛结束了。
Alonso takes the checkered flag.
Alonso冲过终点线。
Alright so F1 racing.
好了，F1赛车。
Erika, do you like it?
Erika，你喜欢吗？
Do you watch it?
你看吗？
Yeah, F1 is pretty neat.
是的，F1挺酷的。
You know, cars that drive fast, that's pretty interesting.
你知道，车开得很快，挺有意思的。
Well for some people it isn't, right, like why do I want to go to a race and just see
嗯，对有些人来说不是，对吧，比如我为什么要去看比赛，就为了看
fast cars?
快车？
Okay, I would never go to a race but I think it's, I would maybe watch the highlights on
好吧，我永远不会去看比赛，但我觉得，我可能会在电视上看一下精彩片段。
TV.
Well actually this year it's really exciting because again we're going to have a night
其实今年真的很激动人心，因为我们要再次举办夜间比赛，我想是在马来西亚或亚洲某个地方，他们要在晚上比赛。
race, I think it's in Malaysia or somewhere in Asia that they're going to race at night.
So that's pretty special, huh?
那挺特别的，是吧？
Well it's like harder to see and you're going really fast, imagine.
嗯，视线更差，而且速度很快，想象一下。
So I hear you're going to the F1 this year.
所以我听说你今年要去看F1。
Yes, this year I'm going to go to the Shanghai circuit to watch the F1 race so I'm really
是的，今年我要去上海赛道看F1比赛，所以我真的很
excited about that.
兴奋。
I haven't ever been to one so it should be fun.
我从来没去过，应该会很有趣。
Alright well I hope you get to see some interesting things like car crashes and pace cars.
好了，我希望你能看到一些有趣的东西，比如撞车和安全车。
What about you guys, our listeners?
你们呢，我们的听众？
Are you fans of F1?
你们是F1迷吗？
Have you ever been to an F1 race?
你们去过F1比赛吗？
Exactly, send us your questions and comments and also your stories.
正是，把你们的问题、评论还有故事发给我们。
I think we have listeners from all over the world.
我想我们有来自世界各地的听众。
We have a lot of listeners in Brazil and I know that there is a Grand Prix there so tell
我们在巴西有很多听众，我知道那里有一场大奖赛，所以告诉我们
us how did it go?
情况怎么样？
Do you like it?
你们喜欢吗？
You can visit us at EnglishPod.com where Marco and I are around to answer your questions.
你可以访问EnglishPod.com，我和Marco会在那里回答你的问题。
Any Canadian race car drivers?
有加拿大赛车手吗？
Yeah, there was one recently.
是的，最近有一个。
Someone, some, something.
某人，某个，什么的。
Alright, maybe our users know which one is the Canadian.
好了，也许我们的用户知道哪个是加拿大人。
So we'll see you guys there.
那我们到时候见。
Thanks for listening.
感谢收听。
Bye.
再见。
You can
你可以